Guide to the Everett Cherrington Hughes Papers 1922-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Nelson, Benjamin, 1968, 1975-1977 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Nelson, Charles, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Nelson, Leona, 1948-1962, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Neugarten, Bernice, 1963-1979 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Neustadt, Ilya, 1965-1968, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - New England Gerontological Society, Eugene A. Friedman, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - New England Sociologist, Susan S. Dibner, 1979-1980 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - New School of Social Research Colloquium, Stanford M. Lyman, 1974-1975 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - New Society, 1965-1967 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Newell, William H., 1961-1968, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Nisbet, Robert A., 1968-1971 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Nishi, Satsuko Matsunaga, 1959-1971 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Nobel, J.D., 1963, 1967, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Noland, William, 1959-1961, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Northeastern Anthropological Association in conjunction with the American Ethnological Society, Fourteenth Annual Meeting, session on "Robert Redfield: his Work and Influence," April 26-28, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Northwestern University colloquium, Howard S. Becker, Margaret Park Redfield, Burleigh Gardner, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - O, general, 1958-1980 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Odegaard, Charles E., 1964-1971 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Offenbach, Lilly, 1963-1970 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Ohio University consultation, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Ohio Wesleyan University, 1961-1979 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Ohio Wesleyan University, honorary degree, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Ohshio, Shunsuke, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Older, Martha, 1963-1964 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Olesen, Virginia, 1964-1973, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, 1974, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Orzack, Louis H., 1959-1965, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Osborne, William A., 1968 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Ostow, Robin, 1971-1980 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - P, general, 1960-1981 (Box 44, Folder 11-14)
  - Papanek, Hanna, 1962-1974 (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
  - Park, George K., 1963-1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Park, Robert E., 1934-1938 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1964-1973 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Paul F. Lazarsfeld Lectures, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Paulin, Helen, 1960-1963 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Peace, pamphlets, 1962-1963 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Peattie, Lisa Redfield, 1963-1974 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Perkins, Sylvia, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Pfautz, Harold, 1963-1976 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Philanthropy and charity, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Phylon, 1960-1976 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Piddington, Ralph, 1958-1962 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Pierson, Donald, 1941-1980 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Portland State College, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Pritchard, Roger, 1960-1971 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Publishers, 1964-1968 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Pulaski, Barbara D., 1972-1977 (Box 46, Folder 6-7)
  - Purser, Noeline I., 1961 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Qualitative Sociology, 1976-1978 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Queen's University, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Quinn, Olive, 1960-1965 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - R, general, 1958-1980 (Box 46, Folder 12-13)
  - Radcliffe College-Massachusetts General Hospital, joint study of nursing education, 1957-1959 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Raushenbush, Winifred, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Ray, Marsh B., 1958-1969 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Record, Jane and Wilson, 1972-1973 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Redekop, Calvin, 1958-1968 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Redfield, James, 1976, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Redfield, Margaret Park (Greta), 1959-1966 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Redfield, Robert, 1958-1959 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Reiss, Albert J., 1960-1968 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Reissman, Leonard, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Reynolds, Larry T., 1968 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Rhie, Touck-Young, 1962-1963 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Rice, John, 1926-1935 (Box 47, Folder 10-11)
  - Richards, Audrey I., 1963, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Richardson, F. L. W., 1962-1982 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Riesman, David, 1942-1949 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Riesman, David, 1950-1954 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Riesman, David, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Riesman, David, 1955-1959 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Riesman, David, 1957-1959 (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1957, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1958-1959 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Riesman, David, Sociability Project, 1958-1959 (Box 48, Folder 7-9)
  - Riesman, David, Harvard House Study, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Riesman, David, 1959-1960 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Riesman, David, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Riesman, David, 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 4-5)
  - Riesman, David, 1960-1962 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1960-1962 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Riesman, David, Committee of Correspondence, Council for Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - Riesman, David, 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 4-7)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1960-1964 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Riesman, David, notes on Japan, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Riesman, David, notes on Japan, 1961-1962 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Riesman, David, 1961-1963 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Riesman, David, 1961-1964 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1962-1965 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Riesman, David, Education Notes, 1963-1964 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Riesman, David, Education Notes, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Riesman, David, Shimer College, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Riesman, David, 1965-1968 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Riesman, David, 1965-1969 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, 1965-1969 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Riesman, David, 1966-1967 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
  - Riesman, David, 1966-1968 (Box 52, Folder 5-7)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, Education Notes, 1966-1969 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Riesman, David, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Riesman, David, 1968-1969 (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
  - Riesman, David, Education Notes, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
  - Riesman, David, 1970-1979 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Riesman, David, 1970-1980 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Riesman, David, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Riesman, David, festschrift, 1975-1976 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Riesman, David, colleges and universities, manuscript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - Riesman, David, "Some Observations on the Interviewing in the Teacher's Apprehension Study," n.d. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Riesman, David, manuscripts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Riesman, Paul, 1964-1975 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Riley, John W., Jr., 1966 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Riley, Matilda White, 1962-1977 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Rioux, Marcel, 1963-1968, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Robbins, Richard, 1972-1973, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Rocher, Guy, 1963-1973 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1951, 1963-1964 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Rose, Arnold, 1959-1963, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Rose, Peter I., 1960-1968, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Rosenthal, Steven, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Ross, Aileen, 1963-1981 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Ross, Robert J. S., 1974-1975 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Rossi, Alice S., 1974-1977 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Rossi, Peter H., 1963-1966 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Roth, Julius, 1955-1966 (Box 55, Folder 3-4)
  - Rothman, Kenneth, 1962-1966 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Roy, Donald, 1946-1956 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
  - Roy, Donald, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Rudolph, Lloyd and Susanne, 1966 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1954, 1963-1968, 1973, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - S, general, 1958-1981 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - S, general, 1958-1981 (Box 56, Folder 1-4)
  - Sagarin, Edward, 1964, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Sanford, Nevitt, 1961-1967 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Sankoff, Gillian, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Sant'Anna, Anna Maria, 1966, 1968, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Sarma, Jyoti, 1959-1969, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Sauermann, Heinz, 1949-1959, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Schiller, Preston L., 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Schneewind, Elsie Hughes, 1971-1972, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - School teachers, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Schudson, Michael, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Schwartz, Barry, 1973 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Schwartz, Morris S., 1963-1965 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Scott, John C., 1970-1971 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Scott, W. Richard, 1960-1975 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Scotton, Carol M., 1974, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Scully, Robert G., 1972-1976 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Seeley, John R., 1958-1971, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Segregationists, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Selvin, Hanan C., 1970, 1975 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Sewell, William H., 1970-1971 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Shaffir, Bill, 1975-1976 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Sharma, Madan Lal, 1959-1966 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Shelkan, Bertie, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Sheps, Mindel C., 1961-1964 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Shibutani, Tamotsu, 1958-1967, 1976-1978 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Shils, Edward, 1975-1976 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Short, James F., 1960-1971, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Sibley, Elbridge, 1957-1979 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Siena College Conference on the Liberal Arts, 1968-1969 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Silverman, Sam, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Simey, T. S., 1962-1964 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Simirenko, Alex, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Simmel, Georg, manuscripts about, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Simmel, Marianne, 1971, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Simmons, Leo W., 1970 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Simon, Rita J., 1964, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Simon, Walter B., 1963-1972 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Singer, Milton, 1972, 1974 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Sir George Williams University, 1966 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Smigel, Erwin O., 1963-1965 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Cyril S., 1965, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Smith, David H., 1970-1980 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Harvey L., 1950-1981 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Social Problems, 1977-1978 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Social Research Conference, ca. 1966 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Social Science at Cambridge University, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1964-1968 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Sociolinguistics, 1963-1974 (Box 58, Folder 21-22)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Sociolinguistics, 1963-1974 (Box 59, Folder 1-8)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Sociolinguistics, 1963-1974 (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology, First Preliminary Conference in Preparation for 1952 Annual Meeting of the Society, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 4-8)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology, 1952, 1962, 1968-1974 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Society for Applied Anthropology, Peter K. New, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Society for the Comparative Study of Society and History, 1966-1967 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Society for Social Research, 1926, 1955-1956 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Society for the Study of Social Problems, 1962-1970, 1975-76 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Society for the Study of Symbolic Interaction, G. H. Mead Award, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Society for the Study of Symbolic Interaction, C. Wright Mills Award, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Sociological Eye, 1970-1971 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Sociological Quarterly, 1969-1978 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Sociological Research Association, 1963-1971 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Sociology of occupations and professions, 1957-1958 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Sociology of religion, 1955-1957 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Sociology of Work and Occupations: An International Journal, 1973-1978 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Sofer, Cyril, 1956-1974 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Solomon, David N., 1938-1974, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Sorokin, Pitirim A., 1967 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - South African Institute of Race Relations, 1957-1977 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Southern Education Reporting Service, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1949 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Soyer, Avron J., 1965, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Spector, Malcolm, 1970-1972 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Spivak, Sydney S., 1958-1969 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Stamler, Jeremiah, 1965-1976 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Stanford University Press, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Starr, Jerold M., 1967-1970, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - State University of New York at Buffalo, Morris L. Fried, 1966-1967 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Stein, Maurice R., 1960-1967 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Steinfelds, Leon, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Stelling, Joan G., 1970-1975 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Stewart, Alice, 1967-1969 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Stewart, Phyllis L., 1970 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Stone, Gregory P., Society for the Study of Symbolic Interaction, 1967-1977 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Stone, Robert C., 1966-1971, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Strauss, Anselm L., 1962-1975 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Robert, 1962-1963 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Strodtbeck, Fred L., 1963-1969 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Study of Applied Anthropology, panel, "Who Studies Whom?," 1974 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Sumner, William G., n.d. (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Survival, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Sussman, Leila A., 1963-1965, 1972, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Sussman, Marvin B. 1964-1967, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Sutherland, David Earl, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Sweetser, Dorrian A., 1964-1967 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - T, general, 1951, 1957-1980 (Box 62, Folder 18-19)
  - Takenaka, Kazuro, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Talbott, John E., 1968 (Box 62, Folder 21)
  - Tanner, R. E. S., 1963 (Box 62, Folder 22)
  - Tax, Sol, 1959, 1964-1968, 1974, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 23)
  - Third World Conference on Medical Education, 1966-1968 (Box 62, Folder 24)
  - Thompson, Edgar, 1939-1981 (Box 63, Folder 1-5)
  - Thorne, Barrie, 1967-1982 (Box 63, Folder 6-8)
  - Thrupp, Sylvia, Comparative Studies in Society and History, 1942, 1952-1971 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Thrupp, Sylvia, Comparative Studies in Society and History, 1942, 1952-1971 (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
  - Tibbitts, Helen, 1959-1962, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Tilley, Charles, 1965-1967 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Tiryakian, Edward A., 1974, 1978-1979, Filder 7: Titmuss, Richard M., 1959-1961, 1968-1973 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Tougaloo College, 1964-1965 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Trans-action, 1967-1968, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Trask, Anne E., 1958-1964, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Triple Revolution, 1964-1967 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Triple Revolution, 1964-1967 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Tropp, Asher, 1961-1965 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Trudeau, Pierre, 1962, 1967, 1969 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Truzzi, Marcello, 1960-1970 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Tuchman, Gaye, 1965-1979 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Tumin, Melvin M., 1968 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Tunstall, Jeremy, 1963-1967 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Turner, Ralph H., 1961-1969, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - U, general, 1957-1980 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1955-1966 (Box 65, Folder 10-12)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1955-1966 (Box 66, Folder 1-5)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), Canadian National Commission for UNESCO, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - United States, Central Intelligence Agency, clippings, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, field reader, 1963-1969 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, National Institutes of Health (NIH), 1959-1963, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, National Institutes of Health (NIH), 1959-1963, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), Field Training Program, 1962-1968 (Box 67, Folder 3-5)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service medical sociology grant, 1963-1968 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - UniversitÈ Laval, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - UniversitÈ Laval, honorary degree, 1977 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, 1962-1963, 1977-1978 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Universities, 1964-1966 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - University of Alabama, 1963-1964 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - University of Alabama, School of Law, 1967-1968 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - University of Bombay, 1957-1968 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - University of Calgary, 1966-1967, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago, 1938-1980 (Box 68, Folder 6-8)
  - University of Chicago, Michael M. Davis Lectureship Fund, 1958-1971 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1960-1980 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago Press, Boys in White, 1960-1964, 1972, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - University of Connecticut, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - University of Kansas, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - University of Kansas, School of Law, 1961, 1963, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - University of Massachusetts-Boston, 1972-1973 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - University of Toronto, 1964-1969, 1979, 1982 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - University of Virginia, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - University of Washington, 1966-1970 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - University of Washington Press, 1969-1970 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1964, 1969 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, Max Weber Colloquia and Symposia, 1978 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Useem, John, 1962-1976 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Useem, Michael, 1973-1974 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Uyeki, Eugene S., 1960, 1969, 1976 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - V, general, 1958-1980 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - van den Berghe, Pierre L., 1965, 1971, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - van Manen, Gloria Count, 1966, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - Vassar College, 1971-1972 (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - Verdet, Paule, 1959-1978 (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Vidich, Arthur J., 1963-1964 (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Violence, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - Vittitow, Richard L., Peace Corps, 1965-1966 (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - Volkart, Edmund H., 1959-1963 (Box 69, Folder 22)
  - W, general, 1957-1981 (Box 70, Folder 1-4)
  - Wacker, R. Fred, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Wadsworth, Homer C., 1957-1972 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Waggoner, George R., 1961-1970 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Wallace, Samuel E., 1965-1966, 1972-1979 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Warner, W. Lloyd, 1959-1978 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Warriner, Charles K., 1962-1965 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Washburn, Sherwood L., 1956, 1962, 1973, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Washington State University, 1964-1967 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Watts, Henry J., ca. 1969 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Wax, Murray and Rosalie, 1954-1976 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Wax, Murray and Rosalie, 1954-1976 (Box 71, Folder 1-5)
  - Weinberg, Julius, 1964-1973 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Weinreich, Uriel, 1964 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Weiss, Robert S., 1959-1981 (Box 71, Folder 8-9)
  - Weller, Forrest, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Wepman, Joseph M., 1960-1962 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Westie, Frank R., 1972-1979 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Westley, Margaret W. and William, 1963-1979 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - White, Leslie A., 1963, 1968, 1973-1974 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Whyte, William F., 1940-1979 (Box 72, Folder 6-8)
  - Wiese, Leopold von, 1946-1962 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Wiggins, Walter S., 1967 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Wilensky, H. and Jack Ladinsky, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Wiley, Norbert, 1976-1982 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Willie, Charles V., 1967, 1975-1978 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Wilson, A. T. M., 1947, 1956 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, Monica H., 1962-1963 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Wilson, Vernon E., 1967 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Wilson, William Julius, 1978 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - WispÈ, Lauren G., n.d. (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1944-1972 (Box 73, Folder 1-2)
  - World Congress of Sociology, 1970, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 3-4)
  - World Future Society, 1974-1976 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Wright, Rolland H., 1963-1972 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Wrong, Dennis H., 1970-1972 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Y, general, 1939, 1962-1975 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Yamamoto, George K., 1958-1979 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, 1967 (Box 73, Folder 10-11)
  - Z, general, 1962-1982 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Zahn, Gordon C., 1963, 1971-1973 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Zakuta, Leo, 1959-1965 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Zinburg, Dorothy, 1970-1973 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Zola, Irving K., 1964-1972 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified, 1960, 1962, 1978, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 5)
- Series III: Course Material
  Series III covers the period 1927 to 1977 and contains course materials. This series has been divided into seven subseries: (1) McGill University, (2) University of Chicago, (3) Brandeis University, (4) Boston College, (5) Visiting Seminars and Lectures, (6) Miscellaneous Lectures, and (7) Student Work.
  The first four subseries correspond to the university teaching posts Hughes held, and the files are arranged by course number and title. The material in the folders includes lectures and lecture notes, syllabi, bibliographies, course outlines, exam questions, mimeographed handouts, course diaries, memoranda, manuscripts by other authors and students, reprints, and newspaper clippings. Prominent subjects of instruction represented in these forms are mass movements and collective behavior, social institutions, professions, race and ethnic relations, and field work. Much of the earlier material from McGill or the University of Chicago is found in the later files reflecting Hughes's continuity of interests.
  Subseries 5 and 6 are lectures not tied specifically to a university or course. These files contain lecture notes and lectures with a few other course materials such as those outlined above. Both subseries are arranged chronologically within subject areas. Subseries 7 contains undergraduate and graduate papers and assignments arranged by students' last names. Titles, courses, or dates are not consistently identifiable.
  - Subseries 1: McGill University, 1927-1938
    - Sociology 6, Social Movements, notes, 1933-1937 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 6, booms, crises, panics, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 6, the crowd, notes, clippings, ca. 1930s (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 6, ecstatic seizures, mass movements, Brother AndrÈ, notes, clippings, 1937 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 6, ecstatic seizures, notes, clippings, 1927-1929 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 6, social unrest, Florida boom, notes, clippings, 1925-1929 (Box 74, Folder 11-12)
    - Sociology 6, mass movements, notes, ca. 1920s (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Sociology 6, miscellaneous reading notes, 1927-1931 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Sociology 6, reform, social politics, public opinion, notes, ca. 1920s (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Sociology 6, reform, strike and revolution, notes, clippings, 1925-1931 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - The Family, notes, including notes from 1924 course by Ernest W. Burgess, 1928 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Immigration, Police and Delinquency, bibliography, exam, courses by Carl Dawson, annotations by Hughes, ca. 1928-1935 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Social Institutions, Press and Public Opinion, notes, course outlines, 1930s (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2: University of Chicago, 1938-1961
    - Psychology 307, lecture, outline, 1960 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Social Science II, "Levels and Directions of Effort," lecture, February 6, 1957 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 201, Collective Behavior and Institutions, syllabus, bibliography, notes, 1938, 1943-1945, 1959 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 210, Study of Society (for Germany), lectures, 1952 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 210, lectures, 1947 (summer), 1952 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 210, lecture, handouts, exams, notes, 1955-1957 (Box 75, Folder 9)